lovemoney.com 2019-12-31

# loveinc..com - Love Incorporated

### This policy

We take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy explains what personal information we collect from you and how we use it.

We encourage you to read this policy thoroughly. To make it easier, we’ve broken it up into bite-size chunks, each with a heading and summary.

### Who is LoveEverything.com Limited

LoveEverything.com Limited is a company registered in England and Wales under company registration number: 07255787.

When we refer to ‘ **LoveEverything** ’ in this Privacy Policy, we mean LoveEverything.com Limited.

LoveEverything is a Data Controller registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office and is responsible for processing the personal information you provide to us on these websites:

<https://www.loveinc.com/>

<https://www.loveincorporated.com/>

<https://www.lovefood.com/>

<https://www.loveproperty.com/>

<https://www.lovemoney.com/>

[https://plans.lovemoney.com](https://plans.lovemoney.com/) (LoveMoney Plans)

If there’s anything you’re unsure about in this Privacy Policy, feel free to contact us at [privacy@loveinc.com](mailto:privacy@loveinc.com)

Details of how Lovemoney.com Financial Services Limited use your data is NOT included in this privacy policy, and you can view that information [here](https://www.lovemoney.com/about/financialservices/privacypolicy).

### Cookies

For information on how we use cookies, please see our separate [Cookie Policy](https://www.loveinc.com/Cookies)

### What information we collect

We will need to ask you for certain personal information to give you the best possible experience when you engage with us (via our websites or otherwise) and when you use our products and services.

We or our third parties will also collect other information about you and the devices you use to access our website. We do this by using technologies like cookies. See also our [Cookie Policy](https://www.loveinc.com/Cookies).

### Contact Information 

When you use the LoveEverything Services we may ask you to provide some contact information. Contact information may include some or all of the following:

Full Name

Email Address

We will only retain this information for as long as there is a continuing need to retain it and will in any case delete it after 2 years of account inactivity.

### Additional Contact Information (for the Lovemoney Plans service)

When you use the Lovemoney Plans service, we will ask you to provide some contact information. Contact information may include some or all of the following:

Full Name

Residential Address

Landline Phone Number

Mobile Phone Number

Email Address

We will only retain this information for as long as there is a continuing need to retain it and will in any case delete it after 2 years of account inactivity.

### Personal Information (for the Lovemoney Plans service)

When you use the Lovemoney Plans service, you may provide some personal information. Personal information may include some or all of the following:

Date of Birth

We will only retain this information for as long as there is a continuing need to retain it and will in any case delete it after 2 years of account inactivity.

### Financial Asset & Plans Information (for the Lovemoney Plans service)

When you use the Lovemoney Plans service, you may provide some Asset & Plans information; this is detailed information about plans, policies, assets, accounts and holdings that you add into your Plans account. Asset & Plans information may include (but is not limited to) some or all of the following:

Type of Asset / Plan (current account, pension, insurance policy etc.)

Reference Number (this could be your credit card or policy number)

Provider Name

Balance or Value

Payments Details (incoming and outgoing)

Detail of funds / holdings

Sums assured

Renewal or Expiry date

We will only retain this information for as long as there is a continuing need to retain it and will in any case delete it after 2 years of account inactivity.

### Documents (for the Lovemoney Plans service)

When you use the Lovemoney Plans service, you upload documents to be stored (in line with our terms and conditions)

We will only retain this information for as long as there is a continuing need to retain it and will in any case delete it after 2 years of account inactivity.

### Security Details

For most of the Services you select on The Websites, we will ask you to provide security information that only you will know. Security information may include a password.

We will only retain this information for as long as there is a continuing need to retain it and will in any case delete it after 2 years of account inactivity.

### Device and Interaction Information

We (Ourselves, via the use of cookies, and via third parties including Adobe Analytics and Google Analytics, whose privacy policies can be viewed here: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=uk](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=uk); <https://www.adobe.com/uk/privacy/policy.html>) may collect certain data automatically about your visit to our website, or use of our Services. This may include but is not limited to the following data: 

  * How you connect to the internet and how you engage with our site
  * Browser data stored on your device (such as cookies, see further detail below)
  * Location data determined using an anonymised version of your IP address, or location information from your mobile device or web browser
  * Information about your web browser such as browser type, browser language, advertising identifier.
  * Information about your device such as device type, operating system, connection speed, internet service provider, and display settings (such as screen size and resolution)
  * Your web browsing activity on our services, including the URLs and names of the web pages you visit on our site, time of day of your visit, time spent on each page, and what you do on them includingwhether you clicked on link, image or text on our site or downloaded a file, image, etc. 
  * The URL of the page that displayed the link that you clicked on, which brought you to our website and the web search you performed that led you to our website
  * Social network profile information
  * Information you may provide on our app, or when interacting with that company’s social media pages, such as information you provide on forms.

We will only retain this information for as long as there is a continuing need to retain it. 

### Application and Server Logs

We store logs of activity on our applications, this isn’t tied to a user but does include the IP address that activity originated from. We use this information to identify and fix issues and to identify and prevent fraud and security issues. 

We will only retain logging information for 30 days 

### How we use your information

We use your personal information in lots of ways to make our products and services as effective as possible. 

We will use your personal information: 

### To enable you to access The Websites and use our services

We will use your information to accept you as a new/returning customer and continue to provide you with our products and services. 

### To provide and improve customer support

We will use your information to be able to provide and improve the customer support we provide to you. 

### For internal training purposes

We will use your information to ensure that our team has the knowledge and expertise to ensure we provide the best possible experience to you when you interact with us 

### For reporting and analytical purposes

We will use your information for reporting and analytical purposes to enable us to improve our products and services and provide appropriate levels of support to our customers 

### For marketing and market research

We will use your information for marketing and market research, such as; If you’ve signed up to receive newsletters and other marketing about our various products and services, or other products and services we feel may interest you, this will be emailed to you. All of our marketing communications will include the option to unsubscribe from us contacting you again.

We may select particular customers and invite them to be involved in market research. If you accept this invitation, we will use the feedback you give us to improve our products and services. 

### To track activity on our website

We will use your information to track your activity on our websites to help us better understand your interests and how you interact with us. To do this we may also place a cookie, web beacon or pixel on pages on our site, or those of our advertisers and partners. This enables us to record in our server logs that a specific user ID has visited a particular page. This data allows us to analyse and determine our audience's behavioural characteristics, which helps us to optimise our site, advertisement placement, and marketing focus.

### To maintain our records and other administrative purposes

We will use your information to ensure that we maintain comprehensive and up to date records of the ways we process your personal information and other operational activities and therefore we will use the information you provide for record-keeping, updates and general administrative purposes. 

### For complaint and dispute resolution

Whilst we will try to make sure that you are happy with the service we provide and do not feel the need to complain, if you do complain to us, we will use the information we have about you to help us manage your complaint and to bring it to a close. 

### To comply with the law

Like any other business, we are required to comply with many laws and regulations. We will, where necessary, use your information to the extent required to enable us to comply with these requirements 

### What are the legal grounds for handling personal information?

In most cases, the information described above will be provided to us by you because you want to take services from us or engage with us and our use of your information will be governed by contract [terms](https://www.loveinc.com/TermsOfUse) . Giving this information to us is therefore your choice. If you choose not to give all or some of it to us, this may affect our ability to provide the services you want, to you.

Where we collect other information from you such as when we use cookies to collect information about the device you use to access our website, or sometimes third parties collect it on our behalf. You will be asked to consent to this before using our website. If you choose not to give your consent, or you later remove your consent, this may affect our ability to provide the services you want, to you.

In the United Kingdom, we can also use personal information where the benefits of doing it are not outweighed by the interests or fundamental rights or freedoms of data subjects. The law calls this the “Legitimate Interests” condition for processing. 

We must comply with various legal and regulatory requirements. Additionally, the service we provide help other organisations to comply with their own legal and regulatory obligations.

We rely on below legal grounds when processing your information:

  * To enable you to access The Websites and use our services,we rely on the legal basis of performance of a contract
  * To provide and improve customer support we rely on legitimate interests to ensure we provide the best possible experience to you when you interact with us
  * For internal training purposes, we rely on the legal basis of legitimate interests to ensure we provide the best possible experience to you when you interact with us
  * For reporting and analytical purposes, we rely on the legal basis of legitimate interests to improve our products and services and provide appropriate levels of support to our customers
  * For marketing and market research we rely on the legal basis of legitimate interests to engage with you in the way you have requested, along with the performance of a contract.
  * To track activity on our websitewe rely on the legal basis of legitimate interests to engage with you and to ensure that you get the best service we can provide
  * To maintain our records and other administrative purposeswe rely on the legal basis of performance of a contract.
  * For complaint and dispute resolution we rely on the legal basis of performance of a contract.
  * To comply with the law, we rely on the legal basis of legal obligation.

We have put in place various safeguards to ensure that individuals’ whose personal information we handle are not unduly harmed by the activities we use their personal data for. These include making information available to individuals so that they understand how their personal data will be used by us, explaining their rights to obtain the information we hold and to have their information corrected or restricted and providing information about how individuals can complaint if they are dissatisfied.

### Further uses of your personal information not described in this Privacy Policy

If we use your personal information for any purposes that are not set out in this Privacy Policy we promise to let you know exactly what we will use it for before we go ahead and use it

### Who we share your personal information with

We do not give, rent, lend or sell individual information to any third party for marketing purposes.

We share your personal information only with those persons who need to handle it so we can provide the LoveEverything products and services you’ve signed up to. We also share it with companies within the group of companies of which LoveEverything forms part; with suppliers who provide services to us which require access to your personal information only; and with resellers, distributors and agents involved in delivering the services we provide where necessary for them to do so.

  * LoveEverything Group Limited Companies – We may disclose information to Lovemoney.com Financial Services Limited and other entities which are subsidiaries, parent companies or otherwise in common ownership with LoveEverything.com Limited. LoveEverything.com Limited is a wholly owned subsidiary of LoveEverything Group Limited (09659887).
  * In addition, we employ the services of third parties to aid us in certain aspects of our operations (such as the distribution of our email products or conducting a survey for us). Depending on the services performed, some of these providers may be provided with user information. These contractors would be subject to data protection and confidentiality agreements which limit their use and disclosure of all information they obtain through their relationship with LoveEverything.com Limited to LoveEverything.com Limited -related business only, consistent with this policy.
  * com Limited community: On The Websites you are publicly identified by your user or screen name. If you choose your full name as your username, you have voluntarily disclosed that information to LoveEverything.com Limited community. Similarly, any information you provide in your public profile is for public consumption. The same is true for any personal identifiable information (such as an email address) you include in any online comments.
  * Current or prospective advertisers/partners: We only provide aggregate, non-identifiable information to our current and prospective advertisers and business partners. For example, we might tell advertisers that we have 120,000 registered members in Metropolis, but we won't tell them that Superman is one of them, and we won't tell them that his email address is ckent@dailyplanet.com.
  * Legal requests: LoveEverything.com Limited may disclose your personally identifiable information to protect the rights and property of LoveEverything.com Limited as well as to comply with any applicable law or valid legal process. This includes, but is not limited to: 
    * requests by government agencies: we will disclose any information we have in our possession to law enforcement or government officials in response to any inquiry or investigation or if in our sole discretion, we believe it is necessary or appropriate in connection with any investigation or activity that is or may be illegal or may expose us or you to legal liability
    * disclosures we are legally required or entitled to make under any enactment, rule of law or by the order of a court
  * Business Sale: In the event that LoveEverything.com Limited sells any business or assets to a third party, we may disclose your personal information to the prospective purchaser.

### Where in the world do we send information?

LoveEverything is based in the UK, and our main databases are located in Dublin and Amsterdam. We also operate elsewhere in and outside the European Economic Area, so we may access your personal information from and transfer it to these locations as well. Don’t worry though, any personal information we access from or transfer to these locations is protected by European data protection standards.

### Your rights to how we use your personal information

You can ask for access to the personal information we hold about you and request that we correct any mistakes, restrict or stop processing or delete it. We will assess your request and subject to legal or overriding requirements to keep it we will act on your request; It’s worth noting that in some cases if you do ask us to correct, delete or stop processing it, we won’t always be required to do so, if that is the case, we will explain why. To request a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please email

In certain circumstances (e.g. where you provide your information to us (a) with consent to process it or (b) where the processing is necessary for the performance of our contract with you) you can require that we provide the information we hold about you either to you or a third party in a commonly used format. This only applies if we are processing it using automated means. If you would like more information about this, let us know by emailing [privacy@loveinc.com](mailto:privacy@loveinc.com).

### Problems with how we handle your information or rights

We will try to ensure that we deliver the best levels of customer service but if you think we are falling short of that commitment, please let us know by contacting us at [privacy@loveinc.com](mailto:privacy@loveinc.com).

If you're still unhappy with any aspect of how we handle your personal information you also have the right to contact the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the supervisory authority that regulates handling of personal information in the UK. You can contact them by:

  1. Going to their website at <https://ico.org.uk/>
  2. Phone on 0303 123 1113
  3. Post to Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, SK9 5AF

You may also have the option to register your complaint using the European Commission Online Dispute Resolution (ODR) platform. This is a web-based platform that is designed to help consumers who have bought goods or services online to deal with issues arising from their purchase.

### How we keep your personal information secure

LoveEverything.com Limited is committed to protecting your personal information. All information that you provide to us is stored on secure servers. Access to any personalised area of the site is password-protected for your privacy and security. While we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

What does all this mean? Just as in the real world, you must protect yourself. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. If you need to change your password, please sign in to the site, go to your personal settings (the link is top-right of any page) and then make the necessary changes.

### How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll keep your personal information for the periods set out in the section ‘ **What information we collect’** above, and where we were not able to give a specific period, we will keep it only as long as we need it to provide the LoveEverything products and services you’ve signed up to. We may also keep it to comply with our legal obligations, resolve any disputes and enforce our rights. These reasons can vary from one piece of information to the next and depend on the products or services you’re signed up to, so the amount of time we keep your personal information for may vary.

All data we store is protected with point-in-time restore functionality, which means that we can restore our databases to the state they were in at any point within the previous 35 days; this is to ensure we can access data in the case of potential data loss or corruption. In reality this functionality is rarely used and if it is every effort will be made to delete again any information that had been deleted from the live database since the restore point. This 35 days that we could potentially restore data from is not included in any other reference to how long we retain your data for.

Details about the logic behind how long we keep your information:

_Contact Information_

Contact information such as email addresses is kept while there is a continuing need for us to have it and is in any case deleted after 2 years of account inactivity.

_Additional Contact Information (for the Lovemoney Plans service ONLY)_

Additional contact information such as full name, residential address etc. is kept while there is a continuing need for us to have it and is in any case deleted after 2 years of account inactivity.

_Personal Information (for the Lovemoney Plans service)_

Personal information such as date of birth is kept while there is a continuing need for us to have it and is in any case deletes after 2 years of account inactivity.

_Financial Asset & Plans Information (for the Lovemoney Plans service)_

Financial Asset & Plans information such as detailed information about plans, policies, assets, accounts and holdings is kept while there is a continuing need for us to have it and is in any case deleted after 2 years of account inactivity.

_Documents (for the Lovemoney Plans service)_

Uploaded documents are kept while there is a continuing need for us to have them and are in any case deleted it after 2 years of account inactivity.

_Security Details_

Security details such as passwords are kept while there is a continuing need for us to have them and are in any case deletes after 2 years of account inactivity.

_Device and Interaction Information_

Device information such as how you connect to the internet and screen resolution are kept while there is a continuing need to retain it. 

_Application and Server Logs_

Application and server logs are only kept for as long as there is a continuing need to retain them. 

In all of these cases, our need to use your personal information will be reassessed on a regular basis, and information which is no longer required for any purposes will be disposed of.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We can update this Privacy Policy at any time and ideally you should check it regularly for updates. We won’t alert you to every little change, but if there are any really important changes to the Policy or how we use your information we’ll announce it on our websites.
